Let us now present a very simple extension of histogram equalization which
现在我们介绍直方图均衡化的一个简单拓展
is called histogram matching. So let us illustrate the problem.
它就是直方图匹配 我们列举一些例子
We saw before, histogram equalization where we take any histogram, any pixel
之前看到过 在直方图均衡化中 我们对任意直方图
distribution, and we match it to something which is as uniform as
任意像素分布 都尽可能与均匀分布的直方图匹配
possible. But imagine that we have this pixel
但是设想我们有这样一个像素分布
distribution, which is the one we have seen before, and somebody comes and tells
就是我们之前看到的分布图 而有人告诉我们
us, this is your target. I don't want to do an equalization.
这个是我们的匹配目标 我不需要做均衡化
I want you to finish with a histogram which is as close as possible to this
我只要处理后的直方图尽可能与这个分布相近
one. So the idea is as before, we're going to
匹配的思想与前面提到的均衡化一样
have to find a map, which is written here.
我们要找到一个映射 就写在这里
This is the map that we have been doing before.
这正是我们之前所做的映射
A map such that from here from this distribution we can go to as close as
这个映射可以让我们将这个分布转换到
possible to this one in this craze, being the way that I'm going to describe
与这个直方图尽量接近 本例中 是变成这个图 很快我会解释这个方法
in a second. What we are going to obtain is this,
我们将会获得这样的分布
which is very similar, not exactly, but very, very similar.
这与目标分布非常相似 并不是完全一致 但是非常的相似
We already saw in the previous video that we cannot always get exactly the
从前面的视频中可以知道 很多情况下我们没办法完全得到指定的直方图
specified histogram. In the previous video, was equalized.
在前一个视频中 目标是均衡直方图
But we can get very close to it. And this is what we see here.
但是我们可以得到很相近的结果 正如这个直方图
So how do we do that? You already have all the tools to do
那么如何匹配呢？ 大家已经掌握了所有方法
that. Let me illustrate how.
现在我来举例说明
We start from the distribution of the current image.
我们从现有图像的像素值分布开始
Whatever that distribution is, it's the image that is given to you.
无论分布怎样 这就是给定的图像
You know how to map that to a uniform distribution.
我们知道怎样把它映射到均匀分布
Okay? Now, you are giving a desire
现在 给定一个分布
You know how to map this desired distribution, the target distribution
我们也知道如何把这个目标分布
also to a uniform distribution. Therefore, if you know how to go from
映射为一个均匀分布 因此 如果知道了怎样从这里映射到这里
here to here and from here to here, if you invert this, you know how to go
和如何从这里映射到这里 如果反转这个过程 我们便能知道
all the path that is the desired path. So, you're going to map a pixel value
整个过程 这是我们的目标 于是我们将一个像素值从这里映射到这里
from here to here, then you're going to ask, okay, where is
也许你想问
this pixel coming from, this pixel value coming from when I want to go here, and
当我们想获得这个分布时 这一像素值从何而来
you just invert that. So, you basically have one map and our
而我们只需求逆映射 所以我们有了一个映射和我们的映射
map and you just invert the second map. So let's say that pixel value a, a pixel
而我们只要反转第二个映射 假设这个是像素值
with a gray value seven goes to ten here. Then you ask, okay, who, from here.
这一像素的灰度值7 转换为这里的10 然后你想问 从这里
What peaks a value, one to ten, and somebody, you know, this map tells you
哪一个像素值转换到10 然后这个映射会告诉你 是15
fifteen. So you end up going from seven to ten,
那么我们就完成了 7 到 10 的转换
and inverse of ten is fifteen, so you went from seven to fifteen.
而 10 求逆得到15 所以我们得到了 7 到 15 的映射
And that's how you basically get a histogram matching.
这就是直方图匹配的方法
Just by doing the histogram equalizations, now you know how to match
通过直方图均衡化 现在我们知道
any two desired distributions. There's one caveat, as we saw in the
如何匹配任意两个给定的分布 这里提醒一下
previous video, the, the maps don't have to be one to one.
正如前一个视频了解的 这个映射不需要是一对一的
So, maybe there is more than one pixel value here that ends up at the same pixel
所以 可能这里有一个以上的不同像素值 映射到那边的同一个像素值
value there. So, when you go from seven, let's say to
所以 从像素值7 假如映射到10
ten, maybe there is fifteen, from here goes to ten.
可能也有一个像素值15 从这里映射到10
And maybe also twenty goes to ten. So.
可能像素值 20 也会映射到 10
Am I going to map seven to fifteen or I'm going to map seven to twenty?
我要将 7 映射到 15 还是 20呢？
You're going to have to make a decision. The most common decision is to pick the
这需要我们决定 最常用的决策是
one that is closest to the original, so you do the less deformation of the pixel
挑选最接近原始值的值 所以我们可以对图像中的像素值做最小的变换
values of the image. But you can make other decisions, as long
但是我们也可以做其他决策
as those decisions are consistent and as long as those decisions guarantee that
只要这些决策保持一致 并且保证
you end up with an increase in function. Remember that we don't want to flip pixel
最后得到一个递增函数 记住我们并不想出现像素值翻转
values. So once again, you do two histogram
我们再重复一遍 先进行两次直方图均衡化
equalizations, you invert one of them. And then you basically obtain histogram
并且对其中一次均衡化求逆 然后完成直方图匹配
matching. So let's see how that works.
我们来看一下匹配的效果
This is a particular example. We have a very dark image here.
这里是一个具体例子 这里有一幅灰暗的图像
And we see that, in the histogram mostly dark values are used.
可以看到 直方图中大多是暗灰度值
So it's hard for us to see what's going on here, because it's very, very dark.
所以我们也难以看到图像的细节 因为它的颜色太暗了
If we do histogram equalization, we get a too bright image as we see here.
如果我们进行直方图均衡化 会得到一个太明亮的图像 如图所示
This is actually the mapping, the T R mapping that we always are looking for.
这正是我们通常寻找的 T(r) 映射
And this is going to be the new histogram.
而这是新的直方图
And we see both from the histogram and from the actual image that it's way too
我们可以从直方图和图像中看到 处理后的图像太亮了
bright. So we haven't achieved what we really
所以我们并没有获得真正想要的图像
wanted which is a nicer looking image that we can actually observe the
我们需要的是一幅更容易观察到不同区域的图像
different regions of that image. If you still have that, we do histogram
还是这幅图像
matching so if somebody comes and tells us I know that this is the distribution
如果有人告诉我们 这个分布可以改善图像
that is going to be great for my image. Then what we do is again, we go form the
我们就可以做直方图匹配 然后再来一次
original distribution to equalization. We go from, this distribution, the new
我们从原始分布得到均衡化分布 再从这个新的分布
distribution here, we go to equalization, which is, going to be this map.
我们进行均衡化 得到这个映射
We invert that map, which is going to be this.
反转这个映射 这就是反映射
And then we go in two steps from the original histogram to the equalized one.
然后我们可以通过两个步骤 先将原始直方图转换为这个均衡化直方图
From the equalized one through the inverse map to the new pixel value.
然后将均衡化的直方图通过这个逆映射转换为新的像素值
And we get this distribution, which gives us this image, which looks much nicer
于是我们得到了这个分布 得到了比这张更清晰的图像
than this one and also help us to look at some of its details.
这个新的图像便于我们观察其中的细节
So we basically got histogram matching by doing twice histogram equalization.
所以我们通过两次直方图均衡化完成了直方图匹配
Once direct and the other which is inverted.
一次是直接均衡化 而另一次需要求逆
And again, if we have ambiguities we just make a decision by using for example, the
而再一次 如果这里出现了多个映射 我们需要决定用哪种映射
pixel value closest to the one that we started in the original image.
比如说可以选择最接近原始图像的像素值
So you got two for the price of one. If you know how to do histogram
真是一箭双雕 如果我们知道怎么做直方图均衡
equalization, you know how to do histogram matching.
也就知道了怎么做直方图匹配
Of course, there is a big art, in designing your target histogram and
当然 设计目标直方图也是一门艺术
that's very application dependent. Let's just mention one last thing about
这个取决于实际需求 让我们提出直方图均衡化
histogram equalization or histogram matching.
或者直方图匹配的最后一个问题
So far, we considered the whole image, and we say, let's just look at the whole
到目前为止 我们考虑的都是整幅图像 我们就看整幅图像
image, let's look at the distribution, and let's match those pixel distributions
关注整体分布 并把这些像素分布匹配到新的分布
to a new distribution, either an equalization or a specified distribution.
进行均衡化或者某一特定分布
You can do the same operations locally. So for example, if we take this, and we
我们也可以在局部作同样的操作 比如
do histogram, global histogram equalization, we're going to get this.
我们对这幅图像 做全局直方图均衡化 将得到这一图像
Sometimes it looks a bit better, but there is a compromise.
有时候它已经看起来好多了 但是效果不甚完美
I only have 256 pixel values to distribute for my whole image.
在整幅图像中 我只有256个像素值来分布
So, I may not be able to do a very strong contrast at the same time here and here.
我可能无法同时在这里和这里都得到较高的对比度
So, the way to solve this is to basically consider regions and say,
所以 解决这个问题的方法是 考虑不同区域
let just do histogram equalization for example of this region and let's do
比如 我们只对这个区域做直方图均衡
histogram equalization of this region. They can actually be overlapping and we
并且对这个区域也进行直方图均衡化 它们可以是重叠的
are going to treat each region independently.
我们会对每个区域进行单独处理
And maybe by doing that, I can basically improve the contrast in every region in
也许通过这个方法 当图像中有很大的灰度变化时 正如这个特殊图像
the image, when there is a large variability, like in this particular
我们也可以提高图像中每个区域的对比度
image. This is the result of that and I want you
这就是处理结果
for example to concentrate on this region.
比如说 注意这个区域
How it's very hard to see the details here.
这里确实难以看到细节
They don't look much better here, but they do look much better here.
这里也没有改善很多 但是这里看起来好多了
Now, in this region, there's not a lot of details.
现在看这个区域 这里看不到很多细节
The global did manage to do a good job but not in this region.
全局直方图均衡化确实有效 但这个区域没有多少改善
Global histogram equalization or global histogram matching is a compromise
全局直方图均衡或者全局直方图匹配是一种折中方案
between everything that we see in the image.
它们对图像的整体进行调节
We can try to overcome, at least partially, that compromise by doing this
我们可以通过局部操作 尝试克服 至少是部分克服这种折中处理的不足
local operation. And now we see that you can get details
现在我们可以看到 这里有明显的细节
here, we can also get details here. So, in the different regions of the
这个区域也有明显细节 所以在图像的不同区域
image, they have very different pixel values and we can still do a basically a
它们有不同的像素值 我们仍然可以进行直方图拉伸
histogram stretching and get much better contrast in the different regions.
在不同的区域都得到更好的对比度
By this, we basically conclude our unit, our portion on histogram equalization and
至此 我们结束了本单元对直方图均衡
histogram matching, a very simple operation, and very useful.
和直方图匹配的学习 这是非常简单而有效的操作
See you in the next video. Thank you.
下次视频见 谢谢 // 果壳教育无边界字幕组 | leafsherry | 风过成伤 | zeadoit